<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Monitor on (bit-mage)</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/tags/monitor/</link><description>Recent content in Monitor on (bit-mage)</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 20:58:12 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rajp152k.github.io/tags/monitor/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I've given up on Monitors</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/no-monitor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 20:58:12 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/no-monitor/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently have moved on from using monitors and am working (professional and writing endeavours) only via a 13 inch laptop. It is definitely a different workflow than what I&amp;rsquo;m used to.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It has been aroud 10 days I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing this and here are some observations:&lt;/p>
&lt;ul>
&lt;li>I&amp;rsquo;m able to focus better as I&amp;rsquo;m forced to enlarge my context maintaining capabilities; for I don&amp;rsquo;t have the luxury to look back and forth with just my eye movements.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I can work from anywhere. I change places and posture every 1.5 hours, 5 times a day.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>Given I move between a couple of meets during the day, I don&amp;rsquo;t have to adjust to differing window management mannerisms as I only ever work on the same screen now.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I work in at most two splits now compared to the 5+ previously: it is all simpler and the monitor has started to seem like a vanity rather than essential accessory.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I don&amp;rsquo;t have to switch keyboards between my desk and meets: I don&amp;rsquo;t mess enough as much now.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I can start looking down upon people that are bound to monitors, thinking that they&amp;rsquo;re spoiled or aren&amp;rsquo;t minimal enough.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I&amp;rsquo;ve started preaching about the spartan-ish effects of working only via your laptop&lt;/li>
&lt;li>I spend more time on screen, on my bed: consequently I&amp;rsquo;m writing more.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ul>
&lt;p>I definitely do miss reading papers and books on a larger vertically oriented screen but I&amp;rsquo;m going to stick to this for a while.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>