<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Habits on Raj Patil</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/tags/habits/</link><description>Recent content in Habits on Raj Patil</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 03:57:29 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rajp152k.github.io/tags/habits/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Definitive Guide to Books</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/the-definitive-guide-to-books/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 03:57:29 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/the-definitive-guide-to-books/</guid><description>Books play a pivotal role in the life of any aspiring and existing intellectual. I began reading diversely and seriously when I was 19 and immediately regretted not starting sooner.
Reading sets you up for an involved existence. If you read vastly, you&amp;rsquo;ll be a force to be reckoned with.
Over the span of 3 years (2019 - 2022), I read around a 100 books ranging from the classics, biographies, auto-biographies, physics, computer science, anthropology, data science, etymology, theology, game theory, mathematics, history, how-to-books, nutrition, physiology , fitness, health, psychology, neuroscience, linguistics, business (okay, don&amp;rsquo;t judge - we all do this), economics, writing, self help (guilty as charged), spirituality, humor (guides to being funny and similar stuff), young adult (only 1 - please don&amp;rsquo;t chastise me - I could not handle the cringe), philosophy (a lot - please don&amp;rsquo;t chastise me) and meta books (speed reading, how to consume books, taking notes, etc).</description></item><item><title>Here we go again...</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/writing-setup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 20:12:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/writing-setup/</guid><description>If you wish to be a writer, write. Epictetus
A Brief History I took up writing as a hobby in the sophomore year of my bachelors and it turned out to be the most definitive step towards bettering my way with words and expressing myself accurately.
This is the fourth major iteration on my blogging system and I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that I&amp;rsquo;m slowly tending towards minimalism and an overall clutter-free approach with each step, building up from my past stylistic mistakes and experiences.</description></item></channel></rss>