<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Raj Patil</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on Raj Patil</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 18:13:15 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rajp152k.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>My Creation and Publishing Pipeline</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/my-creation-and-publishing-pipeline/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 18:13:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/my-creation-and-publishing-pipeline/</guid><description>This is an auxilliary post collating resources for the recent video I posted &amp;hellip;
The Pipeline All the ideas, resources that I want to process, any miscellaneous questions I have, are fed into the input-queue in the buffer All the manipulation takes place in these buffers - they&amp;rsquo;re org-files and I use org-roam to maintain the connections whenever a node set ripens and is worth sharing, I write a post or publish a video.</description></item><item><title>Common Lisp : The Series - 0 : Introduction</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/clts/clts-0/</link><pubDate>Mon, 21 Aug 2023 12:03:07 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/clts/clts-0/</guid><description>This is the first in a series of blog posts that follow the educational common lisp series on my youtube channel as an auxilliary.
I&amp;rsquo;ll be summarizing the videos in these blogs and be using these to point to references and additional resources that further elaborate the matter.
This post is about why you should consider learning common lisp and how I intend to execute the plan of building an end to end resource index while simultaneously being able to learn more about the language myself.</description></item><item><title>RIP, Bram Moolenar</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/rip-bram-moolenar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 18:09:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/rip-bram-moolenar/</guid><description>In memory of the author of vim, arguably the most influential programming utility ever&amp;hellip;
Here is a paper : &amp;ldquo; Seven habits of effective text editing &amp;rdquo; by him that I hope continues to inspire programmers, as it did me when I was a novice.</description></item><item><title>My Emacs Configuration</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/my-emacs-config-0x213b/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 11:23:10 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/my-emacs-config-0x213b/</guid><description>[As of 0x213B : 2023-08-17 Thu]
I use emacs for a lot of my daily tasks and spend majority of my time in it. This is a review of some significant components of my init.el
;keyboard all the way (menu-bar-mode -1) (tool-bar-mode -1) (scroll-bar-mode -1) ;I don&amp;#39;t like distractions (setq byte-compile-warnings &amp;#39;(cl-functions)) (setq ring-bell-function &amp;#39;ignore) (setq visible-bell t) I chose the most recently engineered package-management solution when I began with emacs, haven&amp;rsquo;t switched since and don&amp;rsquo;t think I&amp;rsquo;ll need to.</description></item><item><title>Common Lisp - A Gentle Introduction to Symbolic Computation</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/cl-aitsc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 17:51:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/cl-aitsc/</guid><description>Given I&amp;rsquo;ve passed through SICP once, quickly grasping common lisp to build stuff and explore the traditional and industrial aspects of lisp (I know clojure exists but traditional&amp;hellip;) was my next objective: with decent speed and only solving the somewhat involved exercises, it took me two weeks to complete this book.
The exercises aren&amp;rsquo;t meant to be a challenge but to adapt to the environment and the topics introduced. The book does not explore concepts with depth (CLOS, macros, etc&amp;hellip;) but that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the objective of an introduction anyway.</description></item><item><title>PICC: pragmatics of intellectual consumption and creation</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/picc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 10:40:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/picc/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s a better way to do it - Find it.
Thomas Alva Edison
Managing one&amp;rsquo;s intellectual appetite in these times of information (and noise) excess is quite an ordeal. Given superior tooling and methods to plough through dense knowledge forests, coming up with the right set of tools for oneself is still a commendable task. In this post, I sketch out how one could go about making such choices practically, from why you should bother, to what tangible actions you can get started with.</description></item><item><title>Here we go again...</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/writing-setup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 20:12:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/writing-setup/</guid><description>If you wish to be a writer, write. Epictetus
A Brief History I took up writing as a hobby in the sophomore year of my bachelors and it turned out to be the most definitive step towards bettering my way with words and expressing myself accurately.
This is the fourth major iteration on my blogging system and I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that I&amp;rsquo;m slowly tending towards minimalism and an overall clutter-free approach with each step, building up from my past stylistic mistakes and experiences.</description></item><item><title>About me</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/about/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/about/</guid><description>Hi, This is Raj:
I like maintaining an evolution of my thought process over time and am an arguably extensive dabbler, while trying to master specific domains of course. I believe different knowledge domains are more intertwined than we acknowledge them to be and I find it interesting to build connections.
Albeit a hobby at which I don&amp;rsquo;t particularly excel, writing has been (since I was 19) helping me document my mind and better represent my online presence than any other social media would allow me to.</description></item><item><title>All Posts</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/all-posts/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/all-posts/</guid><description/></item><item><title>I know not ..</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/i-know-not/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/i-know-not/</guid><description>I know not, what is to be known
I know not, what is known
I know not, what I know
I know not, what I don&amp;rsquo;t
I know not, all that I&amp;rsquo;m yet to know.
I know not.
All be it,
that I do know,
is..,
that..,
. . .</description></item><item><title>Now</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/now/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/now/</guid><description>A chronologically descending log of my &amp;ldquo;nows&amp;rdquo; : cause an &amp;ldquo;about&amp;rdquo; isn&amp;rsquo;t enough.
0x2132 As of now, I&amp;rsquo;m laying low and building myself up again. Life is pretty boring and structured : workout, read, work, repeat&amp;hellip; there&amp;rsquo;s not much to it worth discussing.
From a work perspective, am an AI researcher at a cloud computing firm and mostly deal with applications of AI/ML within the same -&amp;gt; am able to study a lot and have some intellectual freedom given it&amp;rsquo;s a growing, modestly large firm and not a fully fledged corporate experience.</description></item><item><title>Résumé</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/resume/</link><pubDate>Mon, 01 Jan 0001 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/resume/</guid><description>As of Thu Oct 6 07:50:21 AM IST 2022:
Education BTECH IIT Hyderabad (2018-2022)
- Major : CSE : 9.26 - Minor : AI : 9.50 Skills Languages: Python, Lisp (Racket, Common Lisp, Elisp), C++, C, Javascript, Haskell, Prolog, Eiffel, Vimscript Tools: git, Unix and GNU philosophies, Make, Emacs, Vim, PostGres, Qiskit Frameworks: Pytorch, Numpy, Pandas, FastAI, cvxpy, Org-Mode, Hugo, Jekyll Experience Towards Transferability Metrics (Aug 2021 - May 2022) - finding a generic transferability score for inter-domain transfer-learning tasks - specific to computer vision applications on chips: in collaboration with KLA Tencor Goldman Sachs Summer Analyst (June 2021 - July 2021) - worked towards improving the cluster interpretability - created a generic multidimensional hyperparameter grid search framework to automate model tweaking CVPR 2021 Workshop paper | AUTONUE 2021 - setting the domain adaptation challenge for semantic segmentation - resulted in a workshop paper: in collaboration with IIIT Hyderabad Projects project desc.</description></item></channel></rss>