<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>rp152k</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/</link><description>Recent content on rp152k</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 05:38:19 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rajp152k.github.io/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Symbols and customized cryptography</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/symbols/</link><pubDate>Thu, 29 Sep 2022 05:38:19 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/symbols/</guid><description>Cryptography, in the mathematical sense, is used in many domains but semiotics (the theory of symbols) is a more powerful personalized approach to encoding messages.
The mathematics bounds the subject to be used only via rigid analytical systems and not fluid malleable ones. I&amp;rsquo;ve found the latter to be more interesting in terms of application and what happens in the real world.
It can be as simple as creating a new domain specific language or reinterpreting old symbols via existing texts.</description></item><item><title>Informal Documentation</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/building-intellectual-bridges/</link><pubDate>Wed, 28 Sep 2022 17:13:21 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/building-intellectual-bridges/</guid><description>Over my past three years of maintaining a healthy intellectual appetite, I&amp;rsquo;ve realized that I learn optimally in iterative cycles of consumption, consolidation and execution.
Expanding individually:
Consumption sweeping the current literature and the fundamentals you may even backtrack along recent ideas to find out the roots of the specific subject Consolidation you let the ideas that you&amp;rsquo;ve consumed simmer in your head this may lead to observing analogies, connections that weren&amp;rsquo;t explicitly consumed by you or seeing opportunities for improvement in existing ideas Execution Learning for its own sake is fun and all but results do matter and completing projects is when one actually learns about the abstract intricacies that are difficult to document.</description></item><item><title>Init</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/init/</link><pubDate>Mon, 26 Sep 2022 16:34:17 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/init/</guid><description>Incentives Precision I&amp;rsquo;m interesting in learning all that interests me in the moment. That usually results me in not being able to deliver for the sake of going under the hood and understanding the nature of the given problem.
Most practical problems do not have an end to the extent to which one can detail the model which they&amp;rsquo;ll use to solve it. It is a waste of energy and time.</description></item></channel></rss>