<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Writing on (bit-mage)</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/categories/writing/</link><description>Recent content in Writing on (bit-mage)</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 20:24:28 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rajp152k.github.io/categories/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Quick Musings</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/quickies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 20:24:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/quickies/</guid><description>&lt;p>From time to time, I do encounter ideas that intrigue my intellect for quite some time.&lt;br>
I do maintain the &lt;a href="https://buffer.thebitmage.com">ideation buffer&lt;/a> to index these ideas into the larger context of my past musings, but I would also like a conveniently accessible chronological search available for cross-domain ideas.&lt;br>
I&amp;rsquo;ll hence be increasing the frequency of premature technical thoughts being packaged into a micro-blogs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I might not elaborate a whole lot in terms of the theoretical aspects of the tooling but I&amp;rsquo;ll be conceptually outlining my current thoughts over the same.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Talking About What You Do</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/talking-about-what-you-do/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 19:30:36 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/talking-about-what-you-do/</guid><description>&lt;p>I haven&amp;rsquo;t been writing quite as much as I&amp;rsquo;d like to lately and have
been considering how I approach the whole thing.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Instead of talking about what I&amp;rsquo;m thinking in the moment (pretty
fleeting), I&amp;rsquo;m &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is exactly the point where I&amp;rsquo;ll go &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m planning on &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; : I do
not wish like doing that anymore. Talking about my momentary plans for
a while has been quite the distraction that I occasionally enjoy.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Converging Expression - thought, speech and the word writ</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/conciser/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 17:26:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/conciser/</guid><description>&lt;p>Speech and the word written, are potential expressions of a
thought. Each one of us enjoys a different mix of how we best convey
ourself.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Ever since I began blogging when I was 19, I&amp;rsquo;ve been prioritising
descriptiveness over precision. I feel I&amp;rsquo;ve entered a
mental state where I value the distilled value of the transmission
more than the exhaustiveness of the message.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I also notice a rift between the way I speak and the way I write. Not
to say that any one of them is superior than the other but I could use
an exercise in convergence - projecting them both onto a common
ground.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Micro-Essays</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/micro-essays/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 14:01:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/micro-essays/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to increase my frequency of writing on the main blog to get
more reps in and converge onto my style quickly than if I continued
with long form content only.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;m also going to practice being more concise, and blogging a little
more on technical aspects as well.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>My usual blog post goes to around 1500-2000 words and that isn&amp;rsquo;t
helpful for covering some minor writing prompts I&amp;rsquo;d like to explore.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Most Important Book You'll Ever Read</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/most-important-book/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 04:05:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/most-important-book/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>To know thyself, is the beginning of wisdom&lt;br>
&lt;em>Socrates&lt;/em>&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="on-tangibility-of-the-past">On tangibility of the past&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>All of us create content, every moment, tuned to varying extents of influence and
permanence.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s intent that separates us all into different leagues of
producers.&lt;br>
Let me explain via a hierarchical build up of selected formats of content with
varying intensity.&lt;br>
Note that the list isn&amp;rsquo;t exhaustive by any means and I&amp;rsquo;ve deliberately
excluded works of larger scale (movies, video games : they have the
potential to be the most influential kind of content out there).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I have a Writing Tutor now ...</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/better-writer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 19:30:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/better-writer/</guid><description>&lt;p>So, I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading a &lt;a href="https://buffer.thebitmage.com/sitemap?stack=%2F20230920144401-prompt_engineering.html">book on prompt engineering&lt;/a> and decided to
practice a little&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s a conversation I had with chatGPT regarding a small essay I
wrote recently and fortunately, there&amp;rsquo;s room to improve.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here&amp;rsquo;s how it went&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="criticize-my-writing-">Criticize my writing &amp;hellip;&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>Raj: You are my writing critic for this session; do not make any intellectual changes in any text I paste; do not heavily influence my style; only analyze what I say and generate pointers as to how I can become a better writer.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Refactoring Old Works</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/refactoring-old-works/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 16:21:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/refactoring-old-works/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;d managed to produce some fairly original essays on my last blog and
I&amp;rsquo;ll soon be incorporating them into posts here. I had a habit of
writing in streams in the main blog itself and there is a lot of
insight stored in the chronology of some such logs.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>The old blog is archived in the repository
&lt;a href="https://github.com/rajp152k/19-22_archive">here&lt;/a> and I could benefit
from repurposing old works into the present setup.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll mainly be focusing on editing the fluff out, finding what good
stylistic knacks I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated over the years, and rejecting the
questionable habits that don&amp;rsquo;t serve me so well.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The Definitive Guide to Books</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/the-definitive-guide-to-books/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 03:57:29 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/the-definitive-guide-to-books/</guid><description>&lt;p>Books play a pivotal role in the life of any aspiring and existing intellectual. I began
reading diversely and seriously when I was 19 and immediately
regretted not starting sooner.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Reading sets you up for an involved existence. If you read vastly,
you&amp;rsquo;ll be a force to be reckoned with.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Over the span of 3 years (2019 - 2022), I read around a 100 books ranging from
the classics, biographies, auto-biographies, physics, computer science,
anthropology, data science, etymology, theology, game theory, mathematics, history,
how-to-books, nutrition, physiology , fitness, health, psychology, neuroscience, linguistics,
business (okay, don&amp;rsquo;t judge - we all do this), economics, writing,
self help (guilty as charged), spirituality, humor (guides to being
funny and similar stuff), young adult (only 1 - please don&amp;rsquo;t chastise
me - I could not handle the cringe), philosophy (a lot - please don&amp;rsquo;t chastise
me) and meta books (speed reading, how to consume books, taking notes,
etc).&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>My Creation and Publishing Pipeline</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/my-creation-and-publishing-pipeline/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 18:13:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/my-creation-and-publishing-pipeline/</guid><description>&lt;p>This is an auxilliary post collating resources for the recent video I
posted &amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;">
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share" allowfullscreen="allowfullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dKU_mNaEo1g?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video">&lt;/iframe>
 &lt;/div>

&lt;h2 id="the-pipeline">The Pipeline&lt;/h2>
&lt;ol>
&lt;li>All the ideas, resources that I want to process, any miscellaneous
questions I have, are fed into the input-queue in the buffer&lt;/li>
&lt;li>All the manipulation takes place in these buffers - they&amp;rsquo;re
org-files and I use org-roam to maintain the connections&lt;/li>
&lt;li>whenever a node set ripens and is worth sharing, I write a
post or publish a video.&lt;/li>
&lt;li>It can go both ways : I can force a set into maturity if I wish to
publish something specific or I may chance upon a concept when
observing connections.&lt;/li>
&lt;/ol>
&lt;h2 id="observations">Observations&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I use &lt;a href="https://github.com/org-roam/org-roam-ui">org-roam-ui&lt;/a> to
visualize the buffer and check for linkages that might result in
something useful. I also want to publish this graph (demonstrated in
video) but there&amp;rsquo;s no explicit solution for that yet and I&amp;rsquo;m planning
to build one myself with rust and webassembly as a compilation
target.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Here we go again...</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/writing-setup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 20:12:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/writing-setup/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote>
&lt;p>&lt;em>If you wish to be a writer, write.&lt;/em>
&lt;em>Epictetus&lt;/em>&lt;/p>&lt;/blockquote>
&lt;h2 id="a-brief-history">A Brief History&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>I took up writing as a hobby in the sophomore year of my bachelors and
it turned out to be the most definitive step towards bettering my way
with words and expressing myself accurately.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>This is the fourth major iteration on my blogging system and I&amp;rsquo;ve
noticed that I&amp;rsquo;m slowly tending towards minimalism and an overall
clutter-free approach with each step, building up from my past
stylistic mistakes and experiences. As with any beginner, I began with
enthusiasm and held my ideas in high regard - a major reason for why I
felt they should be out there. Over time, as I read more, I
learned I had a lot more to learn and finally after a long break of
writing frequently, here I am again, at symbolic ground zero -
drafting a first post.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>