<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Papers on (bit-mage)</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/tags/papers/</link><description>Recent content in Papers on (bit-mage)</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 16:01:03 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rajp152k.github.io/tags/papers/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Skim, Devour, Feynmanize</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/paper-read-strat/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 16:01:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/paper-read-strat/</guid><description>&lt;p>For a while, I&amp;rsquo;d limited my studying endeavours to be project oriented and not domain oriented. While I enjoy the pragmatism of the former, I also wish to build up my innate curiosity to get under the hood, disassemble the engine and be able to put it back together: no project (except the explicit choice of doing so) is going to help me fit that in my studies.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Consequently, I&amp;rsquo;m planning on getting started with a regulary habit of exploring domains with depth.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>The PaperShelf</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/citeread/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 17:38:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/citeread/</guid><description>&lt;p>From time to time, I like to make minor tweaks to my blog based on the treasure trinklets I find around in different corners of the internet from blogs/works of personalities I follow/find interesting.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I got into the practice of logging updates in reverse chronological streams from one of my professors in my sophomore year.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I began personalized hex timestamps (today is 0x2360 for me) because I don&amp;rsquo;t intuitively gel well with the (Julian -&amp;gt; Gregorian) cycles. The combination of lunar, solar and planetary cycles is my most recent experimental initiative for calibrating long term efforts but that would be a little too chaotic for the part of the world wide web that I mostly interact with these days.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>