<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Posts on Raj Patil</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/</link><description>Recent content in Posts on Raj Patil</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 17:51:13 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rajp152k.github.io/post/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Common Lisp - A Gentle Introduction to Symbolic Computation</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/cl-aitsc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 17:51:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/cl-aitsc/</guid><description>Given I&amp;rsquo;ve passed through SICP once, quickly grasping common lisp to build stuff and explore the traditional and industrial aspects of lisp (I know clojure exists but traditional&amp;hellip;) was my next objective: with decent speed and only solving the somewhat involved exercises, it took me two weeks to complete the book.
The exercises aren&amp;rsquo;t meant to be a challenge but to adapt to the environment and the concepts introduced. The book does not explore concepts with depth (CLOS, macros, etc&amp;hellip;) but that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the objective of an introduction anyway.</description></item><item><title>PICC: pragmatics of intellectual consumption and creation</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/picc/</link><pubDate>Tue, 01 Aug 2023 10:40:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/picc/</guid><description>There&amp;rsquo;s a better way to do it - Find it.
Thomas Alva Edison
Managing one&amp;rsquo;s intellectual appetite in these times of information (and noise) excess is quite an ordeal. Given superior tooling and methods to plough through dense knowledge forests, coming up with the right set of tools for oneself is still a commendable task. In this post, I sketch out how one could go about making such choices practically, from why you should bother, to what tangible actions you can get started with.</description></item><item><title>Here we go again...</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/writing-setup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 20:12:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/writing-setup/</guid><description>If you wish to be a writer, write. Epictetus
A Brief History I took up writing as a hobby in the sophomore year of my bachelors and it turned out to be the most definitive step towards bettering my way with words and expressing myself accurately.
This is the fourth major iteration on my blogging system and I&amp;rsquo;ve noticed that I&amp;rsquo;m slowly tending towards minimalism and an overall clutter-free approach with each step, building up from my past stylistic mistakes and experiences.</description></item></channel></rss>