<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Past on (bit-mage)</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/tags/past/</link><description>Recent content in Past on (bit-mage)</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 19:30:36 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rajp152k.github.io/tags/past/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Talking About What You Do</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/talking-about-what-you-do/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 19:30:36 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/talking-about-what-you-do/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t been writing quite as much as I&amp;rsquo;d like to lately and have
been considering how I approach the whole thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of talking about what I&amp;rsquo;m thinking in the moment (pretty
fleeting), I&amp;rsquo;m &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is exactly the point where I&amp;rsquo;ll go &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m planning on &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; : I do
not wish like doing that anymore. Talking about my momentary plans for
a while has been quite the distraction that I occasionally enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Reading an Author</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/reading-an-author/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 16:46:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/reading-an-author/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Do note that this is an old post (from my last archived blog) that I&amp;rsquo;m
refactoring : more on that &lt;a href="https://thebitmage.com/post/refactoring-old-works/"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="the-unaltered-entry"&gt;The Unaltered Entry&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;h2 id="2022-02-01-tue-1011---7946"&gt;[2022-02-01 Tue 10:11] - 7946&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I, hitherto, have been reading books as a single unit of intellectual
conveyance. However, that strategy doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for all the
works. Some authors have their writings crisply intertwined with
their other writings.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Approaching a single book as a part of a larger intellectual
conveyance is more efficient in the longer term if one intends to read
all the work of a particular author. Consequently, grouping these
reads together has also been somewhat interesting lately.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Refactoring Old Works</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/refactoring-old-works/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 16:21:44 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/refactoring-old-works/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;d managed to produce some fairly original essays on my last blog and
I&amp;rsquo;ll soon be incorporating them into posts here. I had a habit of
writing in streams in the main blog itself and there is a lot of
insight stored in the chronology of some such logs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The old blog is archived in the repository
&lt;a href="https://github.com/rajp152k/19-22_archive"&gt;here&lt;/a&gt; and I could benefit
from repurposing old works into the present setup.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll mainly be focusing on editing the fluff out, finding what good
stylistic knacks I&amp;rsquo;ve accumulated over the years, and rejecting the
questionable habits that don&amp;rsquo;t serve me so well.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Definitive Guide to Books</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/the-definitive-guide-to-books/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 03:57:29 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/the-definitive-guide-to-books/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Books play a pivotal role in the life of any aspiring and existing intellectual. I began
reading diversely and seriously when I was 19 and immediately
regretted not starting sooner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading sets you up for an involved existence. If you read vastly,
you&amp;rsquo;ll be a force to be reckoned with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the span of 3 years (2019 - 2022), I read around a 100 books ranging from
the classics, biographies, auto-biographies, physics, computer science,
anthropology, data science, etymology, theology, game theory, mathematics, history,
how-to-books, nutrition, physiology , fitness, health, psychology, neuroscience, linguistics,
business (okay, don&amp;rsquo;t judge - we all do this), economics, writing,
self help (guilty as charged), spirituality, humor (guides to being
funny and similar stuff), young adult (only 1 - please don&amp;rsquo;t chastise
me - I could not handle the cringe), philosophy (a lot - please don&amp;rsquo;t chastise
me) and meta books (speed reading, how to consume books, taking notes,
etc).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Here we go again...</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/writing-setup/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Jul 2023 20:12:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/writing-setup/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;If you wish to be a writer, write.&lt;/em&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Epictetus&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id="a-brief-history"&gt;A Brief History&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I took up writing as a hobby in the sophomore year of my bachelors and
it turned out to be the most definitive step towards bettering my way
with words and expressing myself accurately.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the fourth major iteration on my blogging system and I&amp;rsquo;ve
noticed that I&amp;rsquo;m slowly tending towards minimalism and an overall
clutter-free approach with each step, building up from my past
stylistic mistakes and experiences. As with any beginner, I began with
enthusiasm and held my ideas in high regard - a major reason for why I
felt they should be out there. Over time, as I read more, I
learned I had a lot more to learn and finally after a long break of
writing frequently, here I am again, at symbolic ground zero -
drafting a first post.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>