<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Unix on (bit-mage)</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/tags/unix/</link><description>Recent content in Unix on (bit-mage)</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 14:18:07 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rajp152k.github.io/tags/unix/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Bells &amp; Whistles</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/bells-and-whistles/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 14:18:07 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/bells-and-whistles/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve started spending some time per day without the usual modern software engineering tooling (LLMs, the Internet, etc) to explicitly maintain my cyber-deduction skills (in the context of Unix-based systems (BSDs, Linux, yet to explore Plan9), mostly because they power the majority of the global compute infrastructure).&lt;/p>
&lt;p>It&amp;rsquo;s fun: init your journey with a &lt;code>man man&lt;/code> (I&amp;rsquo;m an &lt;code>info info&lt;/code> guy myself) and be extremely skeptical of your usual modus operandi, ditching all assumptions and tumbling down the rabbit hole.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>I'm in the Business of Ideation</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/gaming-youtube/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 09:01:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/gaming-youtube/</guid><description>&lt;p>People have been responding to emacs and my beard.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>&lt;img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/rajp152k/rpdev/youtube/screenshot_2024-09-17T09:06:11.png?updatedAt=1726544204857" alt="comments">&lt;/p>
&lt;p>For a while I thought I did not have a lot to say. Turns out a lot of other humans are quite interested in the much of the same things that I&amp;rsquo;m into: my hatred for the mouse, and the consequent love for efficient workflows being some of them.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ll give the people what they want: I get to enjoy esoteric tech and spread the word, growing a cult, while other humans have enlightened experiences (believe me I do talk like this in person) and continue propogating the techno-propaganda about enjoying computer science.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Learn Vim the smart way</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/learn-vim-the-smart-way/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 19:18:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/learn-vim-the-smart-way/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been building up my vimrc again because emacs&amp;rsquo; tramp mode just
wasn&amp;rsquo;t cutting it when it came to speed for my remote work
environments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a vim user for around 4 years now and having read some books
partially and sampling a lot of blogs and conference recordings over
this span, I decided I should commit and formally invest into a
definitive resource to get me upto speed and beyond.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>