<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Writing on (bit-mage)</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/tags/writing/</link><description>Recent content in Writing on (bit-mage)</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 09:01:23 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rajp152k.github.io/tags/writing/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>I'm in the Business of Ideation</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/gaming-youtube/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 09:01:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/gaming-youtube/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;People have been responding to emacs and my beard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/rajp152k/rpdev/youtube/screenshot_2024-09-17T09:06:11.png?updatedAt=1726544204857" alt="comments"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a while I thought I did not have a lot to say. Turns out a lot of other humans are quite interested in the much of the same things that I&amp;rsquo;m into: my hatred for the mouse, and the consequent love for efficient workflows being some of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll give the people what they want: I get to enjoy esoteric tech and spread the word, growing a cult, while other humans have enlightened experiences (believe me I do talk like this in person) and continue propogating the techno-propaganda about enjoying computer science.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Quick Musings</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/quickies/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Sep 2024 20:24:28 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/quickies/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;From time to time, I do encounter ideas that intrigue my intellect for quite some time.&lt;br&gt;
I do maintain the &lt;a href="https://buffer.thebitmage.com"&gt;ideation buffer&lt;/a&gt; to index these ideas into the larger context of my past musings, but I would also like a conveniently accessible chronological search available for cross-domain ideas.&lt;br&gt;
I&amp;rsquo;ll hence be increasing the frequency of premature technical thoughts being packaged into a micro-blogs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I might not elaborate a whole lot in terms of the theoretical aspects of the tooling but I&amp;rsquo;ll be conceptually outlining my current thoughts over the same.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Teh worth of a workd</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/free-writing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 10:21:37 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/free-writing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Writing is an involved process. A rough overview is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you think of an idea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you build upon that idea with what you already know&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you structure out some initial drafts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you run it under a careful eye to scrape out the loopholes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you edit it, to the point of satisfaction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with that process is the last bullet right there. It makes
the worth of a word in the moment diminish than the act of etching
something down in stone.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Converging Expression - thought, speech and the word writ</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/conciser/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 17:26:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/conciser/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Speech and the word written, are potential expressions of a
thought. Each one of us enjoys a different mix of how we best convey
ourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since I began blogging when I was 19, I&amp;rsquo;ve been prioritising
descriptiveness over precision. I feel I&amp;rsquo;ve entered a
mental state where I value the distilled value of the transmission
more than the exhaustiveness of the message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also notice a rift between the way I speak and the way I write. Not
to say that any one of them is superior than the other but I could use
an exercise in convergence - projecting them both onto a common
ground.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Most Important Book You'll Ever Read</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/most-important-book/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 04:05:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/most-important-book/</guid><description>&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;To know thyself, is the beginning of wisdom&lt;br&gt;
&lt;em&gt;Socrates&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;
&lt;h2 id="on-tangibility-of-the-past"&gt;On tangibility of the past&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;All of us create content, every moment, tuned to varying extents of influence and
permanence.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s intent that separates us all into different leagues of
producers.&lt;br&gt;
Let me explain via a hierarchical build up of selected formats of content with
varying intensity.&lt;br&gt;
Note that the list isn&amp;rsquo;t exhaustive by any means and I&amp;rsquo;ve deliberately
excluded works of larger scale (movies, video games : they have the
potential to be the most influential kind of content out there).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Prompt Crafting Distilled</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/dense-guide-prompt-engineering/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Sep 2023 16:38:07 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/dense-guide-prompt-engineering/</guid><description>&lt;h1 id="the-premise"&gt;The Premise&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I was initially reluctant on using generative AI for my writing
process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That being said, I was quite aware of the potential of large language
models (generically addressed as LLMs in here henceforth) -
especially true in the case of content creators and/or eccentrically
curious individuals.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I, therefore, decided to clarify how I&amp;rsquo;ll be using generative AI for
my ideation process.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h1 id="the-promise"&gt;The Promise&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Before we get onto that, as promised by the title, distilling the
over-arching skills needed to extract good insights from a
conversation with an LLM (an el-el-em; please don&amp;rsquo;t read it as large, please..).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>I have a Writing Tutor now ...</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/better-writer/</link><pubDate>Wed, 20 Sep 2023 19:30:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/better-writer/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;So, I&amp;rsquo;ve been reading a &lt;a href="https://buffer.thebitmage.com/sitemap?stack=%2F20230920144401-prompt_engineering.html"&gt;book on prompt engineering&lt;/a&gt; and decided to
practice a little&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s a conversation I had with chatGPT regarding a small essay I
wrote recently and fortunately, there&amp;rsquo;s room to improve.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Here&amp;rsquo;s how it went&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;h2 id="criticize-my-writing-"&gt;Criticize my writing &amp;hellip;&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Raj: You are my writing critic for this session; do not make any intellectual changes in any text I paste; do not heavily influence my style; only analyze what I say and generate pointers as to how I can become a better writer.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Definitive Guide to Books</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/the-definitive-guide-to-books/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 03:57:29 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/the-definitive-guide-to-books/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Books play a pivotal role in the life of any aspiring and existing intellectual. I began
reading diversely and seriously when I was 19 and immediately
regretted not starting sooner.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Reading sets you up for an involved existence. If you read vastly,
you&amp;rsquo;ll be a force to be reckoned with.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Over the span of 3 years (2019 - 2022), I read around a 100 books ranging from
the classics, biographies, auto-biographies, physics, computer science,
anthropology, data science, etymology, theology, game theory, mathematics, history,
how-to-books, nutrition, physiology , fitness, health, psychology, neuroscience, linguistics,
business (okay, don&amp;rsquo;t judge - we all do this), economics, writing,
self help (guilty as charged), spirituality, humor (guides to being
funny and similar stuff), young adult (only 1 - please don&amp;rsquo;t chastise
me - I could not handle the cringe), philosophy (a lot - please don&amp;rsquo;t chastise
me) and meta books (speed reading, how to consume books, taking notes,
etc).&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>My Creation and Publishing Pipeline</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/my-creation-and-publishing-pipeline/</link><pubDate>Wed, 23 Aug 2023 18:13:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/my-creation-and-publishing-pipeline/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;This is an auxilliary post collating resources for the recent video I
posted &amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"&gt;
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/dKU_mNaEo1g?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h2 id="the-pipeline"&gt;The Pipeline&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;ol&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All the ideas, resources that I want to process, any miscellaneous
questions I have, are fed into the input-queue in the buffer&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;All the manipulation takes place in these buffers - they&amp;rsquo;re
org-files and I use org-roam to maintain the connections&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;whenever a node set ripens and is worth sharing, I write a
post or publish a video.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;It can go both ways : I can force a set into maturity if I wish to
publish something specific or I may chance upon a concept when
observing connections.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ol&gt;
&lt;h2 id="observations"&gt;Observations&lt;/h2&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I use &lt;a href="https://github.com/org-roam/org-roam-ui"&gt;org-roam-ui&lt;/a&gt; to
visualize the buffer and check for linkages that might result in
something useful. I also want to publish this graph (demonstrated in
video) but there&amp;rsquo;s no explicit solution for that yet and I&amp;rsquo;m planning
to build one myself with rust and webassembly as a compilation
target.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>