<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Philosophy on Raj Patil</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/tags/philosophy/</link><description>Recent content in Philosophy on Raj Patil</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 04:05:55 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rajp152k.github.io/tags/philosophy/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>The Most Important Book You'll Ever Read</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/most-important-book/</link><pubDate>Sun, 01 Oct 2023 04:05:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/most-important-book/</guid><description>To know thyself, is the beginning of wisdom
Socrates
On tangibility of the past All of us create content, every moment, tuned to varying extents of influence and permanence.
It&amp;rsquo;s intent that separates us all into different leagues of producers.
Let me explain via a hierarchical build up of selected formats of content with varying intensity.
Note that the list isn&amp;rsquo;t exhaustive by any means and I&amp;rsquo;ve deliberately excluded works of larger scale (movies, video games : they have the potential to be the most influential kind of content out there).</description></item><item><title>Reading an Author</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/reading-an-author/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 16:46:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/reading-an-author/</guid><description>Do note that this is an old post (from my last archived blog) that I&amp;rsquo;m refactoring : more on that here
The Unaltered Entry [2022-02-01 Tue 10:11] - 7946 I, hitherto, have been reading books as a single unit of intellectual conveyance. However, that strategy doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for all the works. Some authors have their writings crisply intertwined with their other writings.
Approaching a single book as a part of a larger intellectual conveyance is more efficient in the longer term if one intends to read all the work of a particular author.</description></item></channel></rss>