<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>time-stamp on rajp152k</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/tags/time-stamp/</link><description>Recent content in time-stamp on rajp152k</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 15:30:36 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rajp152k.github.io/tags/time-stamp/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>0x2000</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/daysgone/0x2000/</link><pubDate>Wed, 05 Oct 2022 15:30:36 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/daysgone/0x2000/</guid><description>[2022-10-05 Wed 15:31] - my day has a healthy structure now - circadian ryhtms back on track - am waking up again at 530 hrs irrespective of when I sleep - on a week-long break from working out - had accumulated a lot of injuries and inflamation post himalayas - have finally ascribed a purpose to my pursuit of writing - I was writing a book this past summer but scrapped it due to inevitable circumstances - realized quite a few things about how to handle this pursuit of writing while not sacrificing other aspects of my life - this time around, I'll be taking this slow .</description></item><item><title>0x1FFF</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/daysgone/0x1fff/</link><pubDate>Tue, 04 Oct 2022 11:27:50 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/daysgone/0x1fff/</guid><description>[2022-10-04 Tue 11:27] - writing and journalling regularly again - when I archived the last blog, I also scrapped a book that I was working on - the timing wasn't quite right had to give up then - will continue blogging though for some time before I revive that concept again - needed more research and efforts - got to dial down on my career first though</description></item><item><title>0x1FFE</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/daysgone/0x1ffe/</link><pubDate>Mon, 03 Oct 2022 05:47:00 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/daysgone/0x1ffe/</guid><description>[2022-10-03 Mon 05:48] I do enjoy blogging in terms of streams, while keeping it discrete enough for convenient rereads.
- will be initializing a daily stream that I initialize every morning and end at the end of every day. - timestamps somehow increase my awareness of time and delegate the stress of time-management to the computer. - feels like a very simple productivity hack. - I borderline feel like Mark Watney from &amp;quot;Martian&amp;quot;.</description></item></channel></rss>