<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>book on Raj Patil</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/tags/book/</link><description>Recent content in book on Raj Patil</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 19:18:08 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rajp152k.github.io/tags/book/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Learn Vim the smart way</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/learn-vim-the-smart-way/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 19:18:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/learn-vim-the-smart-way/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been building up my vimrc again because emacs&amp;rsquo; tramp mode just wasn&amp;rsquo;t cutting it when it came to speed for my remote work environments.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been a vim user for around 4 years now and having read some books partially and sampling a lot of blogs and conference recordings over this span, I decided I should commit and formally invest into a definitive resource to get me upto speed and beyond.</description></item><item><title>The Hundred Page Machine Learning Book</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/100pagemlbook/</link><pubDate>Tue, 10 Oct 2023 19:40:19 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/100pagemlbook/</guid><description>I couldn&amp;rsquo;t have asked for a denser review of such a technical and diverse domain. It&amp;rsquo;d been more a year since I graduated (majored in computer science and minored in artificial intelligence) and so I decided to brush up on some basics and consolidate what I&amp;rsquo;d studying since the past ~4 years.
I also picked up the book to systematically populate my org-roam buffer and have my root node rooted here in the braindump.</description></item><item><title>Reading an Author</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/reading-an-author/</link><pubDate>Wed, 06 Sep 2023 16:46:47 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/reading-an-author/</guid><description>Do note that this is an old post (from my last archived blog) that I&amp;rsquo;m refactoring : more on that here
The Unaltered Entry [2022-02-01 Tue 10:11] - 7946 I, hitherto, have been reading books as a single unit of intellectual conveyance. However, that strategy doesn&amp;rsquo;t work for all the works. Some authors have their writings crisply intertwined with their other writings.
Approaching a single book as a part of a larger intellectual conveyance is more efficient in the longer term if one intends to read all the work of a particular author.</description></item><item><title>The Definitive Guide to Books</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/the-definitive-guide-to-books/</link><pubDate>Thu, 31 Aug 2023 03:57:29 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/the-definitive-guide-to-books/</guid><description>Books play a pivotal role in the life of any aspiring and existing intellectual. I began reading diversely and seriously when I was 19 and immediately regretted not starting sooner.
Reading sets you up for an involved existence. If you read vastly, you&amp;rsquo;ll be a force to be reckoned with.
Over the span of 3 years (2019 - 2022), I read around a 100 books ranging from the classics, biographies, auto-biographies, physics, computer science, anthropology, data science, etymology, theology, game theory, mathematics, history, how-to-books, nutrition, physiology , fitness, health, psychology, neuroscience, linguistics, business (okay, don&amp;rsquo;t judge - we all do this), economics, writing, self help (guilty as charged), spirituality, humor (guides to being funny and similar stuff), young adult (only 1 - please don&amp;rsquo;t chastise me - I could not handle the cringe), philosophy (a lot - please don&amp;rsquo;t chastise me) and meta books (speed reading, how to consume books, taking notes, etc).</description></item><item><title>Practical Natural Language Processing : Chapters 1-5</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/practical-nlp-c1-5/</link><pubDate>Tue, 29 Aug 2023 16:32:06 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/practical-nlp-c1-5/</guid><description>I took this up when I had to setup a bunch of NLP pipelines for work and this does stand true to its name - it is a quick and practical index into approaches, introductory theory and useful libraries for the same.
I don&amp;rsquo;t like reading text books at a stretch due to several reasons:- &amp;ldquo;cross a bridge, when you get to it&amp;rdquo; is something that has stood the test of time for me when it comes to reading practical books.</description></item><item><title>Common Lisp - A Gentle Introduction to Symbolic Computation</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/cl-aitsc/</link><pubDate>Wed, 16 Aug 2023 17:51:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/cl-aitsc/</guid><description>Given I&amp;rsquo;ve passed through SICP once, quickly grasping common lisp to build stuff and explore the traditional and industrial aspects of lisp (I know clojure exists but traditional&amp;hellip;) was my next objective: with decent speed and only solving the somewhat involved exercises, it took me two weeks to complete this book.
The exercises aren&amp;rsquo;t meant to be a challenge but to adapt to the environment and the topics introduced. The book does not explore concepts with depth (CLOS, macros, etc&amp;hellip;) but that shouldn&amp;rsquo;t be the objective of an introduction anyway.</description></item></channel></rss>