<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Vim on (bit-mage)</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/tags/vim/</link><description>Recent content in Vim on (bit-mage)</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 17:17:59 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rajp152k.github.io/tags/vim/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Thinkpad X13 Gen 4 AMD Ryzen Pro 7840U &amp; Workflow Review</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/new-laptop/</link><pubDate>Thu, 06 Jun 2024 17:17:59 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/new-laptop/</guid><description>&lt;p>I recently shifted my operations to a thinkpad x13g4amd (Ryzen 7840U + 780M Radeon) and am using this transfer as an opportunity to realize and improve my work related habits.&lt;/p>
&lt;h2 id="gnulinux">GNU/Linux&lt;/h2>
&lt;p>All of my pipelines are based around Linux and the core GNU utils. I had to use windows for a while due to org-wide constraints but I&amp;rsquo;ve recently been given the signal to shift to linux.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I rarely used any windows native tools for my workflows and there was always a layer of linux emulation/virtualization (wsl, scoop, and the likes) upon which I conducted my usual operations. Given I use Debian at home, a non native linux experience was frustrating at best and depressing at worst. No more, do I have to confine myself.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>Learn Vim the smart way</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/learn-vim-the-smart-way/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 19:18:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/learn-vim-the-smart-way/</guid><description>&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been building up my vimrc again because emacs&amp;rsquo; tramp mode just
wasn&amp;rsquo;t cutting it when it came to speed for my remote work
environments.&lt;/p>
&lt;p>I&amp;rsquo;ve been a vim user for around 4 years now and having read some books
partially and sampling a lot of blogs and conference recordings over
this span, I decided I should commit and formally invest into a
definitive resource to get me upto speed and beyond.&lt;/p></description></item><item><title>RIP, Bram Moolenar</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/rip-bram-moolenar/</link><pubDate>Thu, 17 Aug 2023 18:09:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/rip-bram-moolenar/</guid><description>&lt;p>In memory of the author of vim, arguably the most influential
programming utility ever&amp;hellip;&lt;/p>
&lt;p>Here is a paper : &amp;ldquo;&lt;a href="https://www.moolenaar.net/habits_paper.pdf"> Seven habits of effective text editing
&lt;/a>&amp;rdquo; by him that I hope continues
to inspire programmers, as it did me when I was a novice.&lt;/p></description></item></channel></rss>