<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>microessays on Raj Patil</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/tags/microessays/</link><description>Recent content in microessays on Raj Patil</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 09:05:15 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rajp152k.github.io/tags/microessays/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Hunt, Feast, Repeat</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/hunt-feast-repeat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 09:05:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/hunt-feast-repeat/</guid><description>I partition my days in phases of different mindsets that allow me to cater to my varying epistemological hungers. One of them is a daily ninety minute ideation hunt and feast that helps keep my skills sharp.
The laws of thermodynamics do form a formidable devil that really does mess up your ordered habits if you do not inject in the necessary energy from time to time.1
As a way to sharpen the intellectual axe, I envision myself going on domain hunts to allot myself a new class of game to look forward to during minor breaks from my usual, comparatively conventional endeavors.</description></item><item><title>Learn Vim the smart way</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/learn-vim-the-smart-way/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 19:18:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/learn-vim-the-smart-way/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve been building up my vimrc again because emacs&amp;rsquo; tramp mode just wasn&amp;rsquo;t cutting it when it came to speed for my remote work environments.
I&amp;rsquo;ve been a vim user for around 4 years now and having read some books partially and sampling a lot of blogs and conference recordings over this span, I decided I should commit and formally invest into a definitive resource to get me upto speed and beyond.</description></item><item><title>Micro-Essays</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/micro-essays/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 14:01:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/micro-essays/</guid><description>I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to increase my frequency of writing on the main blog to get more reps in and converge onto my style quickly than if I continued with long form content only.
I&amp;rsquo;m also going to practice being more concise, and blogging a little more on technical aspects as well.
My usual blog post goes to around 1500-2000 words and that isn&amp;rsquo;t helpful for covering some minor writing prompts I&amp;rsquo;d like to explore.</description></item></channel></rss>