<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>Microessays on (bit-mage)</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/tags/microessays/</link><description>Recent content in Microessays on (bit-mage)</description><generator>Hugo</generator><language>en-us</language><lastBuildDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 16:02:43 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://rajp152k.github.io/tags/microessays/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>One Off ..</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/one-off/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Aug 2025 16:02:43 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/one-off/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I wrestle with boredom from time to time: probably because I maintain a healthy addiction for novelty.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Although my days are scheduled along with a mostly invariable undercurrent of overarching directives, a deliberate portion of &amp;ldquo;something new&amp;rdquo; keeps me engaged and aware in the longer run.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This idea of needing &amp;ldquo;something new&amp;rdquo; everyday has become the most recent constant in my life: to the point of me considering adopting a &amp;ldquo;new new&amp;rdquo; of &amp;ldquo;nothing new for a while and seeing how that feels&amp;rdquo;.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The DocShelf</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/docshelf/</link><pubDate>Tue, 22 Jul 2025 10:46:57 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/docshelf/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Lately realized that I like reading the docs: don&amp;rsquo;t know if such a psychological disorder has been classified so far but I&amp;rsquo;m going to lean into it, for humanity&amp;rsquo;s sake, and document how my condition unfolds.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I, implicitly, have gathered a certain corpus of incommunicable collation of engineering wisdom (/ overenginering foolery?), surfing the architectural and conceptual sections of docs in quite some well-known, mystical, ancient or infamous sections of the internet.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The Un-Unified Heterogenous Irk</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/interfaces/</link><pubDate>Mon, 09 Jun 2025 11:03:25 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/interfaces/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve lately been thinking deeply about how I interact with my computing environments; when working, I&amp;rsquo;ve a&lt;br&gt;
- an unrooted snapdragon ARM Android with Termux and Tmux for ephemeral vimmin &amp;amp; sshing around when on the move&lt;br&gt;
- an Intel x86 FreeBSD home lab for some asynchronous compute that I don&amp;rsquo;t need right away and some redundancy for my important files&lt;br&gt;
- a personal ubuntu VPS with a couple of intel x86 vCPUs for my self hosting endeavours and overall context orchestration&lt;br&gt;
- several compute clusters (avx enabled x86s, ARM, &amp;ldquo;the propietary GPU driver guy on the street&amp;rdquo; GPUs, &amp;ldquo;the other open source GPU driver guy on the steet&amp;rdquo; GPUs, k8s orchestrated production &amp;amp; development playgrounds) for work&lt;br&gt;
- an AMD x86 Tumbleweed with emacs as the daily driver where I actually &amp;ldquo;work&amp;rdquo; : this is desk where I dissect, analyse, reconstruct and dispatch for usage across the above&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Tetris-Complete</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/tetris-complete/</link><pubDate>Fri, 16 May 2025 15:39:43 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/tetris-complete/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Emacs Lisp is &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/spacemacs/comments/dertfg/comment/f2ys9hq/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;amp;utm_term=1&amp;amp;utm_content=share_button"&gt;Tetris Complete&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;did not mean &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/spacemacs/comments/dertfg/comment/f31v6uf/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;amp;utm_term=1&amp;amp;utm_content=share_button"&gt;Turing Complete&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;really did &lt;a href="https://www.reddit.com/r/ProgrammingLanguages/comments/8yct5s/comment/e29v03f/?utm_source=share&amp;amp;utm_medium=web3x&amp;amp;utm_name=web3xcss&amp;amp;utm_term=1&amp;amp;utm_content=share_button"&gt;not&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;</description></item><item><title>Blub in the Unix Philosophy</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/unixier-unix/</link><pubDate>Mon, 24 Mar 2025 15:18:39 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/unixier-unix/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve always maintained a philosophical appetite for the tooling that I use.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;One of the core tenets of the Unix Philosophy&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is that everything is a file&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Plan9&lt;sup id="fnref:2"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; has caught my eye due to its more homogenous design than the usual unix you&amp;rsquo;re used to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The footnoted-paper (~pre-mature book) is somewhat unhinged and doesn&amp;rsquo;t shy away from taking a jab at the Unix ecosystem and design.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Apart from the several points the author makes, what stands out the most for me is the idea of &lt;em&gt;everything&lt;/em&gt; truly being a file: in hindsight, Unix only realizes a fraction of the principle.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Bells &amp; Whistles</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/bells-and-whistles/</link><pubDate>Sun, 23 Mar 2025 14:18:07 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/bells-and-whistles/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve started spending some time per day without the usual modern software engineering tooling (LLMs, the Internet, etc) to explicitly maintain my cyber-deduction skills (in the context of Unix-based systems (BSDs, Linux, yet to explore Plan9), mostly because they power the majority of the global compute infrastructure).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It&amp;rsquo;s fun: init your journey with a &lt;code&gt;man man&lt;/code&gt; (I&amp;rsquo;m an &lt;code&gt;info info&lt;/code&gt; guy myself) and be extremely skeptical of your usual modus operandi, ditching all assumptions and tumbling down the rabbit hole.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>I wrote an Emacs Package</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/fabric-gpt.el/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Mar 2025 19:10:48 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/fabric-gpt.el/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Fabric&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is a collection of crowd-sourced prompts, exposed via a CLI tool. I used it for a while some time ago but never fully exploited it because I prefer Emacs.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Eshell buffers are an option, but I am principled in my tool usage and prefer to delegate longer-running CLI tasks to a combination of Alacritty and Tmux.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Maintaining my Emacs shell usage to ephemeral popups feels natural.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Gptel&lt;sup id="fnref:2"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt; is a versatile LLM client that integrates smoothly into my workflow (buffer/text manipulation and management) without disrupting my thought flow.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Skim, Devour, Feynmanize</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/paper-read-strat/</link><pubDate>Thu, 20 Feb 2025 16:01:03 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/paper-read-strat/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;For a while, I&amp;rsquo;d limited my studying endeavours to be project oriented and not domain oriented. While I enjoy the pragmatism of the former, I also wish to build up my innate curiosity to get under the hood, disassemble the engine and be able to put it back together: no project (except the explicit choice of doing so) is going to help me fit that in my studies.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Consequently, I&amp;rsquo;m planning on getting started with a regulary habit of exploring domains with depth.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>The PaperShelf</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/citeread/</link><pubDate>Sun, 16 Feb 2025 17:38:16 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/citeread/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;From time to time, I like to make minor tweaks to my blog based on the treasure trinkets I find around in different corners of the internet from blogs/works of personalities I follow/find interesting.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I got into the practice of logging updates in reverse chronological streams from one of my professors in my sophomore year.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I began personalized hex timestamps (today is 0x2360 for me) because I don&amp;rsquo;t intuitively gel well with the (Julian -&amp;gt; Gregorian) cycles. The combination of lunar, solar and planetary cycles is my most recent experimental initiative for calibrating long term efforts but that would be a little too chaotic for the part of the world wide web that I mostly interact with these days.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>I'm using Monitors again</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/back-at-monitors/</link><pubDate>Mon, 20 Jan 2025 16:35:52 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/back-at-monitors/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m using &lt;a href="https://thebitmage.com/post/no-monitor/"&gt;monitors again&lt;/a&gt; and it&amp;rsquo;s like consuming caffeine after a long time (last recorded usage circa mid November 2024).&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I guess I need to cycle my dosage so that I don&amp;rsquo;t end up being too dependent.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m enjoying it though.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;blockquote&gt;
&lt;p&gt;EDIT: as of &amp;lt;2025-01-27 17:50:30 IST&amp;gt;, I&amp;rsquo;ve given up again&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;/blockquote&gt;</description></item><item><title>On Achievements</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/achievements/</link><pubDate>Fri, 17 Jan 2025 06:12:55 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/achievements/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I have a somewhat indifferent approach towards achievements(mine and others&amp;rsquo;): with tendencies to gauge the personalities based on how their conversations flow and in terms of the quality of the questions and problems they are working on.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Recently, I&amp;rsquo;ve began to grasp why they actually might be a necessary construct:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;when leading larger societal initiatives, simply claiming ethical superiority doesn&amp;rsquo;t pan out well (and it shouldn&amp;rsquo;t) with the need to gain the trust of masses.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you need displays of competence for people to will their incentives to align with yours somehow (necessary for collective progress).&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;claiming dignity is simply not enough and that is a good thing.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;of course, this opens up a whole bunch of societal games and dynamics that are too complicated for me to completely break down right now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;If you do wish to make a change, you will someday have to take the helm of larger groups of humans. This is when being competent and having proofs for it becomes indispensible.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>I've given up on Monitors</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/no-monitor/</link><pubDate>Mon, 25 Nov 2024 20:58:12 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/no-monitor/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I recently have moved on from using monitors and am working (professional and writing endeavours) only via a 13 inch laptop. It is definitely a different workflow than what I&amp;rsquo;m used to.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;It has been around 10 days I&amp;rsquo;ve been doing this and here are some observations:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m able to focus better as I&amp;rsquo;m forced to enlarge my context maintaining capabilities; for I don&amp;rsquo;t have the luxury to look back and forth with just my eye movements.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can work from anywhere. I change places and posture every 1.5 hours, 5 times a day.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;Given I move between a couple of meets during the day, I don&amp;rsquo;t have to adjust to differing window management mannerisms as I only ever work on the same screen now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I work in at most two splits now compared to the 5+ previously: it is all simpler and the monitor has started to seem like a vanity rather than essential accessory.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I don&amp;rsquo;t have to switch keyboards between my desk and meets: I don&amp;rsquo;t mess enough as much now.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I can start looking down upon people that are bound to monitors, thinking that they&amp;rsquo;re spoiled or aren&amp;rsquo;t minimal enough.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve started preaching about the spartan-ish effects of working only via your laptop&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;I spend more time on screen, on my bed: consequently I&amp;rsquo;m writing more.&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I definitely do miss reading papers and books on a larger vertically oriented screen but I&amp;rsquo;m going to stick to this for a while.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>on Naming your Projects</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/good-names/</link><pubDate>Fri, 22 Nov 2024 14:45:09 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/good-names/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;As an aspiring polymath, you&amp;rsquo;ll soon run out of books and courses if you really wish to explore the intersection of multiple domains based on your current intellectual requirements.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;That is a great problem to have and the solution is to transition into the mindset of chunking your learnings into projects rather than subjects.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll recommend maintaining a sense of pragmatism (incentivize application of what you&amp;rsquo;re learning in the foreseeable future (with non-pedagogical intent)) and haste during your initial iterations. Perfection (The will to tend towards it, rather..) can follow once the prototype is principally sound.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Building (and Maintaining) a &lt;desc. follows&gt; Being</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/building-an-intellect/</link><pubDate>Thu, 21 Nov 2024 17:57:13 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/building-an-intellect/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;One cannot rely on objective standardized tests to gauge how good one is at the act of being.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;They&amp;rsquo;re good to indicate a specific aspect of where you wish to affirm your competence in, but have exhibit numerous fallacies when you&amp;rsquo;re trying to optimize a probabilistic, unstructured, instinct based behaviour over longer spans of durations, ranging from weeks to decades.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Such a gauge is probably only exhaustively captured in how the complexities of life unroll around you based on your behaviours.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Personalized Science</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/personal-research/</link><pubDate>Mon, 18 Nov 2024 11:14:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/personal-research/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I like studying and exploring new things in the spirit of science. The science that happens today in institutions is more than just science and involves a lot of ancillary efforts directed towards the formalized production of research.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I respect formalized scientific efforts but feel like humanity as whole is losing out on the idea of having personalized problem statements to work on without worrying about applications, citations or what the next big thing is going to be.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Temporal Specialization</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/temporal-specialization/</link><pubDate>Thu, 19 Sep 2024 15:32:02 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/temporal-specialization/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;If you&amp;rsquo;re new to the concept of polymathy (I personally ventured into the idea when I read Da Vinci&amp;rsquo;s biography by Walter Isaacson), a lot of counter-intuitive traps await you when trying to build competence in multiple areas.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;You don&amp;rsquo;t need to be a generalist at all times during your journey into polymathy. I mentally grasped this fairly recently that you don&amp;rsquo;t need to shun specializing for smaller durations.
Something like a day is obvious as a candidate but, in the past, I would shy away from even periods of a month to actually focus on a singular thing. I&amp;rsquo;m fairly comfortable doing that for upto three months now but would recommend touching a large span of domains over the span of six months for you don&amp;rsquo;t want to start losing out on the humility that interdisciplinary pursuits enforce on you.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>I'm in the Business of Ideation</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/gaming-youtube/</link><pubDate>Tue, 17 Sep 2024 09:01:23 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/gaming-youtube/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;People have been responding to emacs and my beard.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;&lt;img src="https://ik.imagekit.io/rajp152k/rpdev/youtube/screenshot_2024-09-17T09:06:11.png?updatedAt=1726544204857" alt="comments"&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;For a while I thought I did not have a lot to say. Turns out a lot of other humans are quite interested in the much of the same things that I&amp;rsquo;m into: my hatred for the mouse, and the consequent love for efficient workflows being some of them.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ll give the people what they want: I get to enjoy esoteric tech and spread the word, growing a cult, while other humans have enlightened experiences (believe me I do talk like this in person) and continue propogating the techno-propaganda about enjoying computer science.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Talking About What You Do</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/talking-about-what-you-do/</link><pubDate>Tue, 14 May 2024 19:30:36 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/talking-about-what-you-do/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I haven&amp;rsquo;t been writing quite as much as I&amp;rsquo;d like to lately and have
been considering how I approach the whole thing.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Instead of talking about what I&amp;rsquo;m thinking in the moment (pretty
fleeting), I&amp;rsquo;m &amp;hellip;&amp;hellip;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is exactly the point where I&amp;rsquo;ll go &amp;ldquo;I&amp;rsquo;m planning on &amp;hellip;&amp;rdquo; : I do
not wish like doing that anymore. Talking about my momentary plans for
a while has been quite the distraction that I occasionally enjoy.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>IKN0x221F : Pragmatic Polymathy</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/ikn0x/ikn0x0/</link><pubDate>Sun, 31 Mar 2024 16:00:27 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/ikn0x/ikn0x0/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;&lt;em&gt;Checkout the &lt;a href="https://thebitmage.com/categories/polymathy/"&gt;previous polymathy musings&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/em&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;div style="position: relative; padding-bottom: 56.25%; height: 0; overflow: hidden;"&gt;
 &lt;iframe allow="accelerometer; autoplay; clipboard-write; encrypted-media; gyroscope; picture-in-picture; web-share; fullscreen" loading="eager" referrerpolicy="strict-origin-when-cross-origin" src="https://www.youtube.com/embed/Xl2QISDKhQA?autoplay=0&amp;amp;controls=1&amp;amp;end=0&amp;amp;loop=0&amp;amp;mute=0&amp;amp;start=0" style="position: absolute; top: 0; left: 0; width: 100%; height: 100%; border:0;" title="YouTube video"&gt;&lt;/iframe&gt;
 &lt;/div&gt;

&lt;h1 id="context"&gt;Context&lt;/h1&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I intend to formalize my plans of getting good at multiple domains not
for the reputation that follows but for the generic insight about the
world that you may harness as a result.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This is the second refactor of the way I approach this subject and
this time around I will be pushing for practical indicators that allow
me to gauge my progress over time.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Teh worth of a workd</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/free-writing/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Mar 2024 10:21:37 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/free-writing/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Writing is an involved process. A rough overview is as follows:&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;ul&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you think of an idea&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you build upon that idea with what you already know&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you structure out some initial drafts&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you run it under a careful eye to scrape out the loopholes&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;li&gt;you edit it, to the point of satisfaction&lt;/li&gt;
&lt;/ul&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The problem with that process is the last bullet right there. It makes
the worth of a word in the moment diminish than the act of etching
something down in stone.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Most News is Noise</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/news-noise/</link><pubDate>Sun, 10 Mar 2024 20:37:42 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/news-noise/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I find most sources of information these days (since several years) to
be too noisy compared to the actual signals of wisdom you expect from
a popular source.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Rarely, I&amp;rsquo;ll pull up the news application on my phone and consume a
whole bunch of generic, and some domain specific news.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Other than state of the art research in a technical domain, which is
based upon a corpora of established citations, most other &amp;ldquo;new&amp;rdquo; stuff is
noise.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Converging Expression - thought, speech and the word writ</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/conciser/</link><pubDate>Mon, 04 Mar 2024 17:26:33 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/conciser/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;Speech and the word written, are potential expressions of a
thought. Each one of us enjoys a different mix of how we best convey
ourself.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Ever since I began blogging when I was 19, I&amp;rsquo;ve been prioritising
descriptiveness over precision. I feel I&amp;rsquo;ve entered a
mental state where I value the distilled value of the transmission
more than the exhaustiveness of the message.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I also notice a rift between the way I speak and the way I write. Not
to say that any one of them is superior than the other but I could use
an exercise in convergence - projecting them both onto a common
ground.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Understand Reality and Imparting Meaning</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/understand-v-impart/</link><pubDate>Wed, 13 Dec 2023 17:39:45 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/understand-v-impart/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been formally delving into epistemology and relevant lateral root
domains recently and have been re-encountering several ideas that I&amp;rsquo;d
previously casually explored with intrinsic motivation.&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;This isn&amp;rsquo;t my first accidental implicit intersection of thoughts with
core philosophical theories like constructivist epistemology and
ontology.&lt;sup id="fnref:2"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:2" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;2&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;Given my natural inclinations towards personal interdisciplinary
research, apart from my core specializations, I do deliberately maintain an
extensive scaffolding around several domains that I plan to build
foundations in soon. This allows me to generalize over multiple
realizations of similar concepts in different epistemological clusters
and identify some interesting patterns.&lt;sup id="fnref:3"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:3" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;3&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Hunt, Feast, Repeat</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/hunt-feast-repeat/</link><pubDate>Tue, 12 Dec 2023 09:05:15 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/hunt-feast-repeat/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I partition my days in phases of different mindsets that allow me to
cater to my varying epistemological hungers. One of them is a daily
ninety minute ideation hunt and feast that helps keep my skills sharp.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;The laws of thermodynamics do form a formidable devil that really does
mess up your ordered habits if you do not inject in the necessary
energy from time to time.&lt;sup id="fnref:1"&gt;&lt;a href="#fn:1" class="footnote-ref" role="doc-noteref"&gt;1&lt;/a&gt;&lt;/sup&gt;&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;As a way to sharpen the intellectual axe, I envision
myself going on domain hunts to allot myself a new class of game to
look forward to during minor breaks from my usual, comparatively
conventional endeavors.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Learn Vim the smart way</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/learn-vim-the-smart-way/</link><pubDate>Fri, 20 Oct 2023 19:18:08 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/learn-vim-the-smart-way/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been building up my vimrc again because emacs&amp;rsquo; tramp mode just
wasn&amp;rsquo;t cutting it when it came to speed for my remote work
environments.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve been a vim user for around 4 years now and having read some books
partially and sampling a lot of blogs and conference recordings over
this span, I decided I should commit and formally invest into a
definitive resource to get me upto speed and beyond.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item><item><title>Micro-Essays</title><link>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/micro-essays/</link><pubDate>Mon, 16 Oct 2023 14:01:01 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://rajp152k.github.io/post/micro-essays/</guid><description>&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;ve decided to increase my frequency of writing on the main blog to get
more reps in and converge onto my style quickly than if I continued
with long form content only.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;I&amp;rsquo;m also going to practice being more concise, and blogging a little
more on technical aspects as well.&lt;/p&gt;
&lt;p&gt;My usual blog post goes to around 1500-2000 words and that isn&amp;rsquo;t
helpful for covering some minor writing prompts I&amp;rsquo;d like to explore.&lt;/p&gt;</description></item></channel></rss>